<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</title>
    <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Raman Tehlan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 17:43:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Parkinson&#39;s Law: Getting more things done, fast!</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2021/parkinsons_law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 17:43:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2021/parkinsons_law/</guid>
      <description>Hero image by Nathan Dumlao on Unsplash 
Planning the timeline for a project is one of the hardest things to do. You might have years of experience, but you might still not get it correct. However, with experience, you do get very close to the exact turnaround time. Then, you realize that the best you can do is make the roadmap more adaptable to change. The reason it&#39;s so hard is, the roadmap of any project has so many undefined and unpredictable variables that you can never be sure about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standup - Disagree - Commit</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2021/standup-disagree-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:43:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2021/standup-disagree-commit/</guid>
      <description>Hero image by Desiray Green on Unsplash 
I was recently part of a brainstorming session at work. We planned the session to think of new features in our application. We discussed many ideas, and naturally, I agreed and disagreed with a few of them. And I presented both of them to the team. When the meeting came to an end, we decided on some action items. It also had a few ideas I disagreed with, and I couldn&#39;t understand why we chose to go with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essence of Probability Part - 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2021/mathematics/probability/essence_of_probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 01:05:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2021/mathematics/probability/essence_of_probability/</guid>
      <description>As a kid, I used to play a lot of board games with my cousins. We all would meet on the weekend, sit in the room near the veranda, on the cold marble ground and spend hours playing them. One thing that was common in all the games was dice. For me, it was fascinating to see how many different games we could play with dice. A dice with just six possible values but can turn the tables at any point in the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC 2020: Final Report of nteract play</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/final-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 22:53:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/final-report/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying nteract SDK</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/demystifying-nteract-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 10:38:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/demystifying-nteract-sdk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd Evaluation of nteract-play</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/progress-report-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 10:38:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/progress-report-3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st Evaluation of nteract-play</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/progress-report-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 17:59:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/progress-report-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s it like to strategize and build the sails for nteract-play</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/progress-report-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 16:26:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/progress-report-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Reproducible Computing in nteract Play</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 04:40:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/proposal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The open-source summer of 2020</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 23:26:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/gsoc/intro/</guid>
      <description>On May 4th, 2020, I was trying to focus on my to-do-list for the day while desperately trying not to think about the Google Summer of Code result. Remembering how the last two times I applied, and it didn’t go down well, it unnerved me a little; preparing me better for this year’s results. On one hand, I was frantically refreshing the page, and on the other, I was also exploring something new to pursue and deviate my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulse Journal</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/pulse-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 15:05:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/pulse-journal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern JavaScript Packaging</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/modern-javascript-packaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 11:37:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/2020/modern-javascript-packaging/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, Github announced its Package registry for Javascript and few other languages, which means now you can publish and manage your packages on both Github and NPM and use any package manager client. Through this blog, I will try to explain how you can do it, and by the end, you will know everything to build and publish your package to any registry, Github, or NPM.
 If you are familiar with npm or package building, you can jump directly to the publishing part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Terminal Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/terminalshortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 04:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/terminalshortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Linux is probably the most powerful tool in the world; When I used it for the first time, I instantly felt control over my system, and I started to understand the working of my computer with time. If you are reading this, and are not already using Linux, or haven&amp;rsquo;t used it ever, I strongly recommend you try it out. In Linux, what I like the most is the terminal, it&amp;rsquo;s like magic, it lets you reach the core of your system and work with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Speak</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/howtospeak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 19:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/howtospeak/</guid>
      <description>You have your own set of skills and knowledge, which you collect over time from the education system or through experiencing life. It&amp;rsquo;s also essential to learn to pass it to other people effectively, no one should go out into life without the ability to communicate. Your success in life is primarily determined by:
 Your ability to speak. Your ability to write. The quality of your ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Thinking - Miracle of Innovation</title>
      <link>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 04:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ramantehlan.com/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</guid>
      <description>Today, we need innovation more than we ever did in history. Everybody needs it, whether you are a teacher, global corporation, salesman, entrepreneur, programmer, etc. Everyone needs to get lean and do better with limited resources and time. That is where design thinking comes into the role. Design Thinking can make your mind proactive, and you will become more innovative and creative by the end of this blog. This blog has 4 significant parts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>