<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</title>
    <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 04:17:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/terminalshortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 04:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/terminalshortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Linux is probably the most powerful tool in the world; When I used it for the first time, I instantly felt control over my system, and I started to understand the working of my computer with time. If you are reading this, and are not already using Linux, or haven&amp;rsquo;t used it ever, I strongly recommend you try it out. In Linux, what I like the most is the terminal, it&amp;rsquo;s like magic, it lets you reach the core of your system and work with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Speak</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/howtospeak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 19:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/howtospeak/</guid>
      <description>This blog is a collection of my notes from a lecture on How To Speak by Professor Patrick Henry Winston, MIT. He passed away in 2019, and I am writing this blog in his memory.
 You have your own set of skills and knowledge, which you collect over time from the education system or through experiencing life. It&amp;rsquo;s also essential to learn to pass it to other people effectively, no one should go out into life without the ability to communicate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Thinking - Miracle of Innovation</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 04:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</guid>
      <description>These are notes from an online course taught by Jeanne M. Liedtka, at coursera, created by the University of Virginia.
 Today, we need innovation more than we ever did in history. Everybody needs it, whether you are a teacher, global corporation, salesman, entrepreneur, programmer, etc. Everyone needs to get lean and do better with limited resources and time. That is where design thinking comes into the role. Design Thinking can make your mind proactive, and you will become more innovative and creative by the end of this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>