<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</title>
    <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 19:39:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Speak</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/howtospeak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 19:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/howtospeak/</guid>
      <description>You have your own set of skills and knowledge, which you collect over time from the education system or through experiencing life. It&amp;rsquo;s also essential to learn to pass it to other people effectively, no one should go out into life without the ability to communicate. Your success in life is primarily determined by:
 Your ability to speak. Your ability to write. The quality of your ideas.  This formula determines the quality of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Thinking - Miracle of Innovation</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 04:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</guid>
      <description>These are notes from an online course taught by Jeanne M. Liedtka, at coursera, created by the University of Virginia.
 Today, we need innovation more than we ever did in history. Everybody needs it, whether you are a teacher, global corporation, salesman, entrepreneur, programmer, etc. Everyone needs to get lean and do better with limited resources and time. That is where design thinking comes into the role. Design Thinking can make your mind proactive, and you will become more innovative and creative by the end of this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>