<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</title>
    <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Official Blog of Raman Tehlan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 04:17:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my tiny space on the internet, here I share about my work, life and everything in between. If you are just interested in my career, feel free go directly to my website, to know me more personally you can continue reading my blog.
I&amp;rsquo;m Raman Tehlan, I was first introduced to programming at the age of 11. The first language I used was BASIC, I used it for calculation and to solve simple math problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/terminalshortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 04:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/terminalshortcuts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Speak</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/howtospeak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 19:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/howtospeak/</guid>
      <description>You have your own set of skills and knowledge, which you collect over time from the education system or through experiencing life. It&amp;rsquo;s also essential to learn to pass it to other people effectively, no one should go out into life without the ability to communicate. Your success in life is primarily determined by:
 Your ability to speak. Your ability to write. The quality of your ideas.  This formula determines the quality of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-1: Introduction to Data Mining</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/data-mining/part1-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 21:43:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/data-mining/part1-introduction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 0424: Data Mining</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/data-mining/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 14:51:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/data-mining/introduction/</guid>
      <description>A blog series on Data Mining, which I will publish in 5 parts. I will be taking reference from many places, listed at the bottom of this blog. This is just the Introduction blog and will give you an overview of what will be covered in this series.
Part 1: Introduction to Data Mining  Tasks Issues Decision Support System Dimentional Modelling Data Warehousing OLAP &amp;amp; its tools OLTP  Part 2: Mining Techniques &amp;amp; Clasification  Introduction Statistical Perspective of Data Mining Decision Tree Neural Networks Genetic Algorithms Issues in Classification Statistic Based Algorithm(Regression) Distance Based Algorithm Decision Tree Based Algorithm(C4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Fail</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/howtofail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 19:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/howtofail/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyData NYC - 2019</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/pydatanyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 19:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/pydatanyc/</guid>
      <description>PyData NYC I really messed up my talk; I kinda feel it should not even go live, that&amp;rsquo;s the last thing I want my parents/friends or me to see. I think I am bad at calculating situations, I really need to fix it, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to feel like this again. I wish I could go back in time and change stuff, but I can&amp;rsquo;t, so all I can do now is make the future better and make things work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Thinking - Miracle of Innovation</title>
      <link>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 04:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramantehlan.github.io/blog/post/designthinkingmiracleofinnovation/</guid>
      <description>Today, we need innovation more than we ever did in history. Everybody needs it, whether you are a teacher, global corporation, salesman, an entrepreneur, programmer etc. Everyone needs to get lean and do better with limited resources and time. That is where the design thinking comes in the role. Design Thinking can make your mind proactive, and you will become more innovative and creative by the end of this story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>